<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on xrazis · Haris Razis</title>
    <link>https://haris.razis.com/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on xrazis · Haris Razis</description>
    <image>
      <title>xrazis · Haris Razis</title>
      <url>https://haris.razis.com/</url>
      <link>https://haris.razis.com/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://haris.razis.com/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Migrating a Plesk server with multiple production environments.</title>
      <link>https://haris.razis.com/posts/server-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haris.razis.com/posts/server-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been maintaining a managed Plesk server on a Greek hosting provider for the past few years. It contains a handful
of production websites and their respective mail servers. While it was okayish for basic hosting needs, the demands
quickly outgrew it with limitations starting to appear on the infrastructure, supported technologies, and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a little market research, I decided that the way forward would be Digital Ocean, as they provide solid cloud
infrastructure with a plethora of tools. I also decided to keep Plesk as the server
management platform. It will be adequate for the low needs of basic Node.js sites and small eshops, with the
added benefit of an embedded mail server, security features, automations, and backups.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Unifi connections</title>
      <link>https://haris.razis.com/posts/debugging-unifi-connections/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haris.razis.com/posts/debugging-unifi-connections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having SSH access to the server you are battling with is an invaluable tool - no matter how feature-rich the console may be. In the few past days, we (my father and I) faced connectivity issues on a corporate network where a specific client (a POS device) would not stay attached to the nearest access point but instead hop to an AP further away. That caused connectivity problems with slow/failed transactions. It finally proved to be a miss-configuration issue (as it always is) but had we had proper logging, we could have resolved the issue much sooner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unresolvable host workaround with resolved.conf</title>
      <link>https://haris.razis.com/posts/resolved.conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haris.razis.com/posts/resolved.conf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I encountered a weird issue the other day at work where I could not resolve a specific dev server on my laptop. Despite
being logged to the company&amp;rsquo;s VPN and being able to resolve all the other servers, this specific one stubbornly
refused. Going through the debugging process of a complex network was not an option, so &lt;code&gt;resolved.conf&lt;/code&gt; came to the
rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;network-name-resolution-configuration-files&#34;&gt;Network Name Resolution configuration files&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The file &lt;code&gt;resolved.conf&lt;/code&gt; is responsible for local DNS and LLNMR (Link-Local Multicast Name Resolution) name resolution.
The main file can be found under &lt;code&gt;/etc/systemd&lt;/code&gt; and its entries override any defaults. The following configuration was
needed for the server to resolve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable IoT solution for real-time body position tracking</title>
      <link>https://haris.razis.com/posts/ichnaea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haris.razis.com/posts/ichnaea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while ago I submitted my thesis with its subject being the study of the architecture of BAN and PAN, and their
applications, with the aim of optimizing athletes performance, by enhancing personalized training practices. I was also
tasked with creating an e-sport application that would collect and analyze data on the athlete’s body position in
real-time. I named the e-sport application Icnhaea, and I will be referring to it as so for the rest of this post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
